（キバ）ばあさん　入るぜ。
I'm coming in, Granny.
これ
娘さん夫婦から預かってきた。
This is from your daughter
and her husband.
おや　すまないねぇ。
Oh my, thank you.
こっちは手紙だ。
（赤丸）ワン　ワン！
Here's a letter for you.
ワン！
（ナルト）おっ　キバ。
Hey, it's Kiba.
（サクラ）里の人たちのために→
I hear he volunteered to act as
a messenger
キバ君　自分から
連絡係を買って出たらしいわよ。
for the people of the village.
あいつら
いつも　一緒にいやがんな。
Those two are always together.
あんただって　あったじゃない。
え？
You were too...back then.
Huh?
ほら…
サスケ君と　ずっと一緒のとき。
Remember? When you were
completely stuck to Sasuke.
そりゃ　同じ第七班だったから
サクラちゃんだって…。
That's 'cuz we were both on Team 7.
So were you...
違うわよ。　ずっと一緒で…。
I don't mean that.
This was different.
You two were inseparable, literally.
離れられないほど…。
あぁ！　あった！
Now I remember!
そうだってばよ
あのとき　俺たちは→
That's right. That's the time
we were on a mission
盗賊に盗まれた
大名の妹だかの宝物を→
to retrieve the treasure belonging to
the Feudal Lord's sister or whoever,
which had been stolen by thieves.
取り返そうって　任務についてた。
- Leaf's History -
The Worst Three-Legged Race
（カカシ）情報によると
妹君の黄金像を盗んだ賊は→
According to our Intel,
the thieves who took the golden statue
陸路をとって　この森の道か→
are either traveling on land
through this forest path
水路をとって　この船着き場の
どちらかに現れる可能性が高い。
or sailing by boat and will land here.
で　俺たちは先回りをし
二手にわかれて待つ。
We're going to split up into
two teams and lie in wait for them.
ま…　バランス的に言って→
In terms of balance,
俺１人に
お前たち　３人ってとこかな。
I guess I should go alone and
the three of you will be together.
それってば　どういうこと？
What do you mean by that?
Are you saying Sasuke needs
all the help he can get?
サスケが足引っ張っちゃうから
そうなんのか？
（サスケ）違う　お前だ。
No, you're the hindrance.
俺は　あんたより
今は劣っている。
I'm not up to your level yet,
but surely 3 to 1 is too much.
だが　３対１ほどの差はない。
足手まといのナルトを
そっちにやって→
Why don't you take Naruto
off my hands?
マイナス分を互角にする。
それで　どうだ？
Subtract his skill from yours,
and we'll be even.
えぇ！　それって　サスケ君！
Huh?!
Sasuke, is that just
a clever approach
私と　２人っきりになりたいって
大胆なアプローチなの！？
so that you and I
can be alone together?!
くぬぅ～…
ふざけんなってばよ！
You've got to be kidding!
なんで俺が　引き算になんだよ！
Why would you subtract my skill?!
お前に　プラス材料などない。
なに～！？
Because you have nothing to add.
What?!
きゃ～！
私と一緒にいたいからって→
Sasuke wants to be with me so much,
he's getting impatient!
サスケ君が熱くなってる～！
お前も　うっとうしい！
You're just as irritating!
（カカシ）はい　注目。
Okay, pay attention.
で　俺は　この船着き場。
I'll watch the pier.
お前たち３人は
森の　この道を張る。
And you three will keep an eye
on this path in the forest.
賊が現れたら
まずは俺に知らせろ。
If the thieves appear,
notify me immediately.
たかが盗人と侮るな。
Do not take them lightly.
俺たちの目的は
あくまで黄金像の奪還だ。
Our mission is to retrieve
the golden statue.
慎重に　事にあたらねばならない。
We must proceed with utmost caution.
俺のほうに賊が現れても
合図を送る。　こいつでな。
If the thieves appear on my side,
I will send a signal with this.
この雷筒を空に放てば→
When this lightning barrel
is tossed into the air,
１発だけ
雷を鳴らすことができる。
it will release one thunderbolt.
こいつを確認したほうは
速やかに現場に急行すること。
Once you verify it,
rush straight to that location.
取り扱いには
すっご～く気をつけろよ。
You better handle that with care.
いいな。　くれぐれも
勝手なことはするなよ。
Now remember.
You are not to act alone.
《盗賊団だ…》
It's the gang of thieves!
うわっ！
（ジャコ）てめえ！　この野郎！
Why you...
Idiot!
大事なお宝背負ってるんだぞ！
Careful with the treasure!
すいやせん　ジャコの頭！
I'm sorry, Boss Jako!
（ジャコ）しっかりしろい！
へい！
Shape up!
Yes sir!
《お宝…！？　あの葛篭に？
Treasure?! In that wicker box?
これってば…　チャンス！》
This is...my chance!
すごい！　ナルト君。
Amazing, Naruto!
サスケ君に差をつけちゃったみたい！
ニヒヒ…。
You showed up Sasuke real good!
《あいつも　まさか…！？
Don't tell me he's up to the same...
負けねえってばよ》
I won't lose to him!
うわっ！
なんだ！？
W-What's this?
しまった　お宝が！
Damn! The treasure!
《何やってるのよ　２人とも！
What are those two doing?!
カカシ先生に知らせるのが
先でしょう！》
We have to notify
Kakashi Sensei first!
ん？　仲間か　チッ。
What? There's another?
お宝を放せ！
Let go of the treasure!
放すかってばよ！
くらえ！
No way!
Take this!
I won't lose it.
逃すか！
え？
Huh?
クソ…。
Damn it.
木ノ葉の追っ手か。
Pursuers from
the Hidden Leaf, eh?
仲間は　あの２人だけか？
Were those two
the only ones with you?
まだ仲間はいるんだろう？
There must be others.
だから　この場所を
知らせようとした。
That's why you tried to get word out
about this location.
おもしれえだろ　俺はな→
Cool, huh?
I'm a natural-born thief
who's rotten to the core.
根っからの泥棒で
性根が腐ってるんだ。
So as you can see,
even my chakra is foul.
だからよ　俺のチャクラもこんなふうに
腐って出てきやがる。
やつら２人は川下に逃れた。
Those two escaped downriver.
We'll split up and concentrate our search
along the river and we'll find them.
川を中心に手分けして捜す。
お宝を取り返すぞ。
（スグロ）こいつは　どうしやす？
And we'll take back the treasure.
What about her?
人質に使えるかもしれん
一緒に連れて行く。
We might be able to use her
as a hostage.
Bring her with us.
そんな　くだらないもんを
よくも盗む気になったってばよ。
I can't believe they stole
something stupid like this.
雷。
え？
The thunder...
Huh?
カカシに知らせる雷
鳴らなかったよな。
The thunderbolt to signal Kakashi
didn't go off, did it?
No.
あぁ　うん。
サクラ　鳴らせなかったのか？
Maybe Sakura couldn't release it.
サクラちゃんが捕まった！？
Sakura's been captured?!
- Huh?
Wha-?
（２人）なんじゃこりゃ～！？
- What is this?!
どうなってるんだ　これ。
W-What's going on?
くっついちまってるぞ。
We're stuck together.
（２人）せ～の…。
- Ready...pull!
おぉ～！
Why is it always with you?!
なんでこう　お前なんかと！
That's my line!
それは　こっちのセリフだ！
ヘヘ　安心しろ。
もうじき　仲間に会わせてやる。
Don't worry.
You'll see your friends soon.
お宝を返してもらったら→
After they return the treasure
仲よくあの世に
送り届けてやるぜ。
I'll send you to the afterlife together.
忍とて　手がつながったままじゃ
どうすることもできまい。
Even ninja are helpless
if their hands are bound.
《サスケ君　ナルト》
Sasuke... Naruto...
サクラちゃん…。
Sakura...
こうしてる間にも
サクラちゃんが…。
While we're stuck like this,
Sakura could be...
You idiot, Naruto!
バカ　ナルト！
サクラちゃん
俺が助けに行くってばよ！
Sakura... I'm coming to save you!
待て　バカ野郎！
Wait! You fool!
何するってばよ　サスケ！
What the hell are
you doing, Sasuke?!
お前　サクラちゃんが
どうなってもいいってのか！
Don't you care what happens
to Sakura?!
サクラは助ける。
We will save Sakura!
But we can't do anything if
our hands are like this.
だが　この手じゃ
どうしようもないだろう！
We're going to save her despite that.
It's what friends do!
それでも　助けに行くのが
仲間ってもんだろうが！
俺は…。
I...I don't want to be some scum who
doesn't give a damn about his friends!
仲間を大切にしないクズになんか
なりたくはねえ！
((仲間を大切にしないやつは
それ以上のクズだ))
Those who abandon their friends
are worse than scum.
Then joining up with Kakashi
is the right move to make!
だったら　カカシと合流するのが
いちばんの得策だ！
サクラの生存確率も上がる！
It will increase Sakura's chance
of survival!
生存確率なんて言うな！
Don't talk about
her chance of survival!
俺たちの頑張り次第じゃ
ねえのかよ！
It just depends on how hard
we want to save her!
こんなもののために
サクラちゃんが！
We can't let Sakura die
over something this stupid!
You idiot! Stop it, Naruto!
バカ野郎！
やめろ　ナルト！
この！
Damn it... Damn it... Damn it...
くそっ　この！
まぁ　任務を大切にしないやつも
クズだけどな。
You know, a guy who doesn't take
his mission seriously is also scum.
おしっこ。
ハァ！？
Gotta pee.
What?!
だから
おしっこだってばよ！
I said, I need to take a leak!
何しやがる！
Hey, what the hell?!
え　だって…。
じゃあ片手で。
Uh...well...
Okay, one hand then.
ふざけろ　こんな近くで！
ひっかかったらどうする！
Cut it out! Not so close!
What if you spray me too?!
I don't care what you say.
If I gotta go, I gotta go.
んなこといったって
出るもんは　しょうがねえだろ。
我慢しろ！
我慢できねえって！
Hold it in!
Can't.
いいから　ちょっとだけ…。
しまえ　この野郎。
- Just let me finish, okay? Come on.
- Zip up, you idiot!
うわぁ～！
（２人）ぐぐぐぐ…　うわっ！
邪魔だ　ナルト！
You're in my way, Naruto!
お前が
俺の邪魔してんだろうが！
You're the one who's in my way!
お宝を　返しやがれ！
Give back the treasure!
うわっ！
多重影分身の術！
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
ううっ！
片手で　印を結べるかよ。
言ったろうが！
Like you can weave a sign
with one hand!
Didn't I tell you?
この状況じゃ
こんな格下相手でも→
At this rate,
we don't have a chance,
どうすることも
できないんだよ！
even against guys much
weaker than us!
ナルト　待て！
Naruto...wait!
俺は　行く！
I'm going.
嫌なら…
俺の手を切ってでも行く。
If you refuse...
I'll cut off my arm, then go.
こいつを倒して
サクラちゃんを助けるんだ！
I'm going to beat this guy
and save Sakura!
ぬ～っ！　ふん！
うわっ！　くっ！
ムチャしやがって！
You're so reckless!
うっ！　うぅ～！
俺は行くぜ！
サクラちゃんを助けに。
I'm going to save Sakura.
敵が　ここまで　やってきた以上→
Since the enemy came this far,
カカシに　たどり着く前に
見つかるとみていい。
we'll probably be found before
we catch up to Kakashi.
だったら　こいつから
やつらのいる場所を聞き出して→
If that's the case,
it'll be faster if we make this guy tell us
where Sakura is and save her.
サクラを助けたほうが早い。
サスケ…。
Sasuke...
それも
俺とお前の　コンビネーション次第だが。
Though it'll depend totally
on us working together.
ハハ…。
あぁ！
Right!
ううっ…　思い出した。
Oh, I just remembered.
I gotta pee.
おしっこ。
うっ…。
はぁ～。
俺もだ…。
Me too.
ヘッヘッ。
なに？
スグロのやつが　戻ってこねえだと？
What? Suguro hasn't come back?
へぇ～　もしや…。
I wonder if he...
その　もしやだよ！
だってばよ！
You're wondering right.
Yeah!
《サスケ君！　ナルト！》
Sasuke! Naruto!
Huh?
クッ！
ヘヘン。　やっと　自由になれた。
Free at last.
さすが
大名の妹君所有の黄金像だ。
Only a Feudal Lord's sister
could own a gold statute like that.
こいつが　俺たちを
引き離してくれたぜ。
It managed to pull us apart.
やつらの手が　自由になった？
Their hands are free now?
こいつは　くれてやる。
You can have it
だが　そこにいる仲間と交換だ。
in exchange for our partner.
要求をのまなけりゃ→
If you don't agree
自由になった　この手で
全員　ぶっ倒してやるってばよ！
I'll pulverize every one of you,
now that my hands are free.
忍２人に→
Surely you don't think that
mere robbers can beat two ninja?
盗賊風情が
勝てると思ってるわけ→
ないよな？
ヘッ。
何を　そんなに
歯を食いしばってる？
How come you're gritting
your teeth so hard?
（ジャコ）青筋立てて　汗かいて…。
Your veins are popping out
and you're sweating.
（２人）くっ…。
自由なら　こっちに来てみろよ！
If you're free,
come over here.
さぁ！
Come on!
こいつらの手は
まだ　つながったままだ。
Their hands are still fused!
恐れることはねえ。
ひっとらえろ！！
There's nothing to fear!
Get them!
バレちまったら…。
しようがねえってばよ！
He called our bluff!
Can't help it!
Why you...
Wha-?!
うわぁ！
うわぁ～！
ナルト！
おう！
- Naruto!
- Right!
ちっ…。
危ない！
Oh no!
（サクラ）２人とも　よけて！
Look out, you two!
お宝は　俺のものだ！！
The treasure is mine!
片腕だけでも封じる！
We can stop at least one of his hands.
いくぞ！
おう！
- Let's go!
- Right!
させるかってばよ～！！
Oh no, you don't!
火遁！
影分身の術！
Fire Style!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
なんだと？　印を？
What?! A seal?
な～んてな！
２人で印を組んだって→
Even if we can weave signs together,
we can't mold chakra.
チャクラを練ることは
できないんだよ！
ふざけやがって！！
Why you... Taking me for a fool!
でも　コンビ技はあるぜ！
But we do have a combination attack!
なにっ！
What?!
Pachinko Jutsu!
パチンコの術！！
ヘヘヘヘ！
（カカシ）まぁ　溶かして作り直せば→
Well, I guess it can be
melted down and re-cast.
ギリギリいけるか。
Just maybe.
（サクラ）ありがとう　サスケ君！
Thank you, Sasuke!
え～！　俺だって　頑張ったのに…。
Hey, I did my best too.
冗談じゃねえってばよ！
This is ridiculous!
カカシ先生でも外せねえなんて。
How come you, of all people,
can't undo this, Kakashi Sensei?!
まぁ　あの頭も言ってたじゃない。
Remember, that boss said so too.
２～３日すれば
崩れてボロボロになるって。
It'll crumble apart in
two or three days.
そんな長い間
こいつといられるか！
Like I can put up with him
for that long!
それは　俺のセリフだってばよ。
ハハハハ！
That's my line.
Uh-oh... I think I need to go.
やばい！　もよおした…。
またか！
Not again.
This time it's number two.
今度は
おっきいほうだってばよ。
You've got to be kidding.
冗談じゃねえ！　やめろ　ナルト！
Don't you dare, Naruto!
まぁまぁ　まぁまぁ。
Aw c'mon, we already peed together.
一緒に　つれしょんした
仲じゃねえか。
大きさが違う！
《仲間を
大切にしないやつは　クズか。
こいつらは
軽々と　それをやってのける》
（一同）せーの！せーの！
＜生涯　終わることのない道＞
＜　それぞれの職人という仕事＞
＜　その技を高めていくたびに
人生の意味を見いだしてきた…＞
＜和風総本家…＞